Neal, you'll be running forever.
닐, 도망다녀야 해
영원히
모든 걸 제자리에 돌려놓을 방법이야
This is a way to set things right.
We're going home.
집에 가는 거야
집에 가죠
복귀 첫 날인데, 기분은 어때?
First day back. How you feeling?
상쾌한데요?
I'm feeling pretty good.
다리가 괜찮은 덕분인가봐
I can tell. The limp's about gone.
맞아요, 조금 당기긴 하는데
Oh, yeah. There's still some tension,
그렇다고 산책도 못할 정도는 아니에요
but it's nothing I can't walk off.
산책에 알맞은 도시를 잘도 골랐네
Picked the right town for it.
산책이야 말로 뉴욕에 다시 적응 하기에
가장 완벽한 방법이죠
Casual stroll is the perfect excuse
to get reacquainted with New York,
그 도시의 언어에 적응하기에도 좋고요
speak the city's language again.
Ooh, wow. What'd the city say there?
그래서 도시가 뭐라 해줬어?
돌아오신 걸 환영합니다
"Welcome home."
When do you sit down with Hughes?
휴즈 요원님과는 언제 약속이 있으세요?
출근하자마자
The second we get in.
마음에 들지 않아요
I don't like this.
시작하지도 마
Don't start.
전 돌아가는데 요원님은 조사나 받고
재배치를 받으시다니요?
I go back to work,
and you're placed under
review and reassigned?
장담하건데 잠시뿐일 거야
I'm sure it's only temporary.
도망갔던 사람은 저라고요
I'm the one who ran.
분명히 내게 그러지 말라고 했는데도
널 쫓아간 사람이 바로 나잖아
And I'm the one who went after you
when I was explicitly told not to.
I don't know where they're sending me.
어디로 보낼진 모르는 거잖아
강력계,마약단속국
사이버 범죄 수사국일지도 모르지
It could be Organized Crime, Vice, VCU.
May not be that bad.
나쁘지 않을 수도 있잖아
And you're fine with that?
그게 괜찮으시다고요?
글쎄, 받아들이기엔
괜찮은 시기라고 생각해
Well, the timing could
be better, I'll admit.
오, 이런 일에 괜찮은 시기라는 게
있기나 하는 건가요?
Oh, I'm sorry. Was there a
better time for this to happen?
그런건 아니고, 사건을 다시 재개할
계획을 세우고 있었어
No, but I was planning on reopening a case,
and I don't want anything
slipping through the cracks.
어떤 실수라도 없었으면 하는 바람이야
제가 조사해 볼 수 있을 것 같아요
Maybe I can look into it.
복잡한 문제이기도 하고
더 이상 내가 상관할 바도 아니야
It's complicated, and it's out of my hands.
하루 쉬어버려요
Take the day off.
됐어, 가자고
No, no. Come on. Come on. Keep walking.
Your new assignment.
자네 배정지 일세
You're sending me to the Cave?
저를 케이브로 보내 신다고요?
내가 손쓸 수 있는 가장 최선의
장소가 바로 증거물 보관소 일세
It's the evidence warehouse,
and it's the best I could do.
사법부에서 이번 사건을 정리할 때 까진
Justice won't allow you
to work active cases
자네가 밖에 돌아다니는 걸 원하지 않을거야
until they sort it out.
닐은 어떻게 되는거죠?
What about Neal?
자네 팀이 맡게 될 걸세
Your team will handle him.
제가 담당했던 사건은요?
My caseload?
존스와 다이애나가 처리중이야
Jones and Berrigan are on it.
이번주에...
'Cause you know this week --
그래, 자네에게 그 사건이
얼마나 중요한지 잘 아네
Yeah, yeah. I know how
important it is to you.
그리고 말야
Look, another thing --
윗선의 몇몇분들이 자넬 쳐내려고
벼르고 있는 것 같아
Some of the top brass may
be looking for an excuse
to shut you out.
처신 잘해
Don't give them one.
부서 전원이 최대한 빨리
자네가 복귀하길 원하고 있어
Everybody wants you back
here as soon as possible.
So, you know, work the Cave.
그러니 케이브에서
잠자코 일이나 하고 있어
Keep your head down.
- 알아들었나?
- 네
- Got it?
- I got it.
증거물 보관소라...
힘들어봤자 얼마나 힘들겠어요
Evidence. How bad can it be?
버크요원이군
You must be Burke.
패터슨 요원님 이시죠
You must be agent Patterson.
피터라고 불러주세요
Uh, you can call me Peter.
늦었군
You're late.
네, 지금 막 배치 받았거든요
Yeah, I just got the assignment.
잡담은 그만하고 일하러 가지
Well, let's skip the small
talk and get to work.
이 곳이 잘 굴러가게 하는 것 말고도
자네 보모 노릇까지 하게 생겼구만
In addition to keeping this place running,
now I've got to babysit you
and file daily reports
for your review board.
게다가 자네 위원회에
일일 보고서도 써야 하지
정말 그게 필요한 일인가요?
Is that really necessary?
화이트칼라에서는 자네 명령에 대해
일일이 설명해 주나 본데
Your orders may have been
open for interpretation
back at White Collar, but not
here, so get used to it.
여긴 아니야, 그러니 적응하게
Okay.
알겠습니다
출퇴근 기록계 일세
You punch in. You punch out.
1분이라도 늦게 출근하거나
1분이라도 일찍 퇴근한다면
You arrive a minute late,
you leave a minute early,
책임져야 해, 변명은 필요없어
you answer to me --
No excuses.
그리고 자네에게 기한을 정해주면
어떻게 해서든 맞춰야 해
Also, if I give you a deadline,
you make damn sure you meet it.
규정위반은 전부 보고서에 쓰일거야
One infraction, it goes in my report.
알겠습니다
I understand.
이게 제 임무이군요?
This is my assignment?
새로 입수한 휴대전화들이야
Fresh batch of hot cellphones.
심 카드별로 분류해 주게
I need you to catalogue them by SIM card.
No problem.
문제없죠
좋아
Good.
Hey! Bring in the rest of them!
이봐! 나머지 가져와!
알겠습니다!
Yes, sir!
금요일 아침까지 해줬으면 해
Your deadline's Friday morning.
케이브에 온 걸 환영하네, 버크
Welcome to the Cave, Burke.
제가 방해가 될까요?
Am I interrupting anything?
닐, 여기서 뭐해?
Hey, Neal. What are you doing here?
존스랑 다이애나가 점심시간을 줬거든요
Jones and Diana gave me a lunch break.
요원님이랑 같이 먹었으면 좋겠다 싶었죠
I figured you could use one, too.
그러고야 싶지
Oh, I'd love one, but
I-I got to finish this.
헌데 할 일이 산더미라...
알았어요
All right.
음... 할만 하세요?
How's it, uh... how's it going for you?
최고야, 이제 2000개 밖에 안남았거든
Great. I've only got 2,000 more to go.
Wow. All right.
You're sure you don't want a break?
정말 안쉴거예요?
아니, 좀 쉬자
Yeah, I do want a break.
내가 이 말을 하게 될 거라곤
생각도 못했었는데 말야
You know, I didn't think I'd
have to say this out loud,
내 증거물 보관소에 범죄자라니
but no convicted felons
in my evidence locker.
꺼져, 카프리
You leave, Caffrey.
간단히 먹을 것좀 가져온 것 뿐입니다
Just bringing him some take-out, sir.
그렇다면 밖에서 먹지 그러나
Well, then I suggest you take it outside.
어디서요?
Where?
피크닉 에어리어에서
The picnic area.
훌륭한데요
Sounds nice.
눈부신 햇살에 상쾌한 공기,
그리고 철조망이라
The sun is shining. Fresh air. Barbed wire.
이 모든게 그걸 떠올리게 하네요...
It all kind of reminds me of...
- 말하기만 해봐
- 교도소 마당이요
Don't say it.
...The yard.
이게 어떻게 교도소 마당이야
This is not a prison yard.
너라도 프랑스 테이크아웃 요리는
감옥에서 못구한다고
You can't get French take-out in a prison.
저 오리콩피 먹은 적 있어요
I got duck confit once.
아, 테이크아웃은 아니었네요
Wasn't take-out, though.
신선하게 데친 오리였으니까요
It was fresh-poached, actually.
감옥에 있는게 아냐, 닐
재배치 받은 것 뿐이야
I'm not in prison, Neal. I'm reassigned.
여기서 열심히 하고 싶을 뿐이야
And I'm not making any waves.
그게 이곳에서 가장 빨리
나갈 수 있는 방법이거든
That's the fastest way out of here.
갑자기 생각났는데 말야
Which reminds me --
너랑 하고 싶은 얘기가 있었어
there's something I want
to talk to you about.
네 감형심리때 내가 진술하기 전에
Before I gave my statement
at your commutation,
나한테 모든걸 말해주겠다고 약속했었지
you promised you'd tell me everything.
제가 자유의 몸이 될 거라고
생각했을 때 했던 말이에요
When I said that, I thought
I was gonna be a free man.
그래, 어쨌든 약속은 한거네
Yeah, but you said it.
그러니 말해봐
So start talking.
제 아버지에 대해 좀 알고 계시죠
You already know about my dad.
응, 경찰이셨잖아
Yeah, he was a cop.
부패한 경찰이셨어요
He was a corrupt cop.
Ellen was his partner.
엘렌이 파트너였구나
맞아요
Yeah. She also arrested him.
아버지를 체포한 사람도 바로 그 분이시죠
무슨 죄로 체포했던건데?
What'd she arrest him for?
저도 다 알진 못해요, 아셨죠?
I don't know everything, all right?
버크!
Burke!
어떤 녀석이 압수된 잉크 카트리지가
가득 들어있는 상자를 두 개나 엎었네
Someone spilled two full cases
of seized ink cartridges.
얼른 가서 치우게
I need you to get inside and clean it up.
점심시간으로 한 시간 주셨잖아요
You said I get an hour for lunch.
오늘 아침에 30분 늦었으니
어떻게든 채워야 하지 않겠나
Well, you were a half-hour
late this morning.
This is how you make it up.
나중에 얘기하자
햇살님이 내가 필요하다네
To be continued. Sunshine needs me.
행운을 빌어요, 멋쟁이 아저씨
Good luck with that one.
Charmer.
이봐요
Hey, guys.
무슨 일이에요, 카프리?
What is it, Caffrey?
오늘 아침에 요원님이
This morning Peter mentioned
옛 사건들 중에 하나를
재수사 할 계획이라고 하시더라고요
that he'd planned to reopen one
of his old investigations.
제가 살펴보고 싶은데요
I'd like to see it.
이미 두 사건이나 맡겼잖아요
We already gave you two assignments.
아, 신용사기건 말이죠
계좌를 탈취한 거였어요
Oh, yeah. Your credit fraud.
It's account takeover.
전화를 걸어 피해자들의
우편 주소를 바꾸고 나서
Guy's changing the
victims' mailing addresses
새로 카드를 보내달라고 하는 수법이죠
over the phone, then
requesting replacement cards.
- 다른 하나는요?
- 파산 사기에요
And the other one?
Bankruptcy fraud.
첫 번째 피의자가 자산을 숨긴거예요
Primary suspect's concealing assets
사촌 이름으로 된
예금 계좌를 통해서 말이죠
through a checking account
in his second cousin's name.
요원님이 재배치 된 건
순전히 제 잘못 때문이에요
Look, it's my fault
Peter's been reassigned.
아주 잘 알고 있어요
I know that.
적어도 제가 할 수 있는건
요원님께 해당되는 일이라면
The least I can do is try
to help solve something
제가 도와드리는 거라고요
that matters to him.
정말 같이 하고 싶어요?
You sure you want in on this?
그럼요, 어서 파일이나 보죠
Yeah, let's see the file.
Okay.
오케이
Light.
간단하네요
Okay.
오케이
하나 더요
One more.
와우, 이거 말이에요...
사건은 하나 인거죠?
Wow. That's, uh -- that's one case?
네, 아직 해결되지 않았죠
Yep. Still unsolved.
얼마나요?
For how long?
20년 동안이요
20 years.
일 하기 위해서 밀린 공부 좀 할게요
Guess I got some catching up to do.
한글수정: sweetmin
수정금지 배포자유
해설/피드백:khbs22.tistory.com
White Collar S04E03"Diminishing Returns"
Original Air Date On 2012. 7. 24.
부서에서 이 신출귀몰한 녀석을
쫓은지 20년이나 됐죠
The bureau's been after this
mystery thief for two decades.
밀린 공부는 다 했어요?
Are you up to speed?
녀석의 첫 범행은 부쉬윅에서
은행 금고를 털은거죠
All right, his first heist was a
securities vault in Bushwick.
현금으로 3백만 달러에 단독범행이죠
Got $3 million in cash -- one-man job.
5년 뒤에 브롱스에 있는
지역금융은행을 목표로 삼았죠
Five years later,
he targeted a Region
Financial Bank in the Bronx.
560만 달러였고요
Hit it for $5.6 million.
다시 5년이 흐르고 나서
Another five years goes by,
녀석은 방탄 처리된 트럭을 수송중에 덮쳐서
he robs a brink's truck in transit
4백만 달러 어치의
무기명 채권을 가지고 도망가죠
and makes off with $4
million in bearer bonds.
용의자도 없고 말이에요
And we have no suspects.
두 가진 알고 있어요
We know two things, though.
첫 째로 녀석은 5년마다 나타나는데
이제 나타날 때가 다 됐어요
First, he surfaces every five
years, almost to the day.
이런 패턴에 집착하는 녀석이라면
If he sticks to this pattern,
it means he's gonna pop
up sometime this week.
이번주에 나타난다는 뜻이죠
그래서 요원님이 그렇게
걱정하고 계셨던거군요
That explains why Peter was so concerned.
그가 5년 동안 또 사라지기 전에
작은 기회라도 얻은 셈이죠
We got a small window
before this guy disappears
for five more years.
5년이라...
Five years.
공소시효가 지나가길 기다리는 거예요
He's waiting for the statute
of limitations to pass.
만약에 잡히더라도 하나의 범죄에 대한
처벌만을 받는 다는 걸 잘 아는거죠
He knows if he ever gets caught,
he can only be charged with one crime.
가중처벌을 피하는 거예요
No compounded sentences.
두 번째로 알고 있는 건 뭐죠?
What's the second thing we know?
각각의 현장에서
특정한 담배 증거물이 발견됐어요
At each scene, there was a
specific tobacco residue.
딱 이걸 제외하고는
지문이나 섬유는 없었고요
No print, no fibers, nothing
except trace amounts of this.
터키쉬 하모니라, 고가품이네요
Turkish Harmony -- high-end stuff.
요원님이 연관점을 찾아내셨어요
Peter made the connection.
10년 전에 은행 강도 사건을 맡으셨을 때
He was assigned a bank
robbery 10 years ago,
담배를 발견하신거죠
found the tobacco.
나중에 담배 브랜드를 통해
기록을 검토해 보셨더라고요
He searched records for hits
on the brand afterwards.
이게 패턴을 발견하게 된 경위에요
It's how he found the patterns
in the previous heists.
어느 정도 조사를 하고 나서
After some research,
요원님은 이 모든게 내부 범죄라고
생각하시더라고요
he began to think it was all an inside job.
오, 요원님이 은행에 잠입수사를 했었네요
Oh. Says here Peter went
undercover at the bank
for a few weeks after it was robbed.
은행이 털리고 나서 몇 주 뒤에 말이죠
네, 위장 했던 이름이 피터 모리스에요
Yeah. Cover I.D. --
Peter Morris.
알아낸 게 있었나요?
He find anything?
글쎄요, 그 분이 하셨던 거니까
가서 여쭤보는게 어때요
Well, he's the expert. You should ask him.
어딜 가시려고 하시나?
Where do you think you're going?
집이죠, 퇴근시간이잖아요
Home. My shift's over.
시계는 아직 1분 남았다고 하네만
Clock says you have a minute to go.
정말요? 제 시계를 보면...
Really? 'Cause according to my watch --
일찍 퇴근 하려 한다는 말은
You'd be leaving early.
위원회에 올릴 자네 보고서에도
그 말이 기록 된다는 걸 뜻하네만
Which would have to go into my daily report
for your review board.
- 이젠 가도 좋네
- 좋은 저녁 보내세요
- Now you can go.
- Have a good night.
Exciting day?
재밌으셨어요?
글쎄, 너무 일을 많이 해서 손에
통증이 가실 날 없는 사내들의 하루랄까
Well, it's a thrilling tale
of a man's battle with
carpal tunnel syndrome.
I hate to take you away from that,
그냥 일하시게 놔 둘걸
어쨌든 도움이 좀 필요해요
but I need your expertise.
새로운 사건이라도 맡았어?
You have a new case?
One of Peter Morris', actually.
사실은 피터 모리스 요원의 사건이죠
그것 참 교묘한 위장이었지
Oh, that was a tricky cover.
지점 매니저의 친 형제인 척 했었어
I posed as the branch
manager's brother-in-law.
마치 촉망받는 신입사원처럼 보였지
Made it look like a favor hire.
거기다 전과 기록도 조금 넣어뒀지
And I gave myself a little rap sheet.
현명한 행동이죠
Oh, smart move.
대화 도중에 그런 불량스런 과거를
살짝 흘리셨겠죠
You let your wayward history
slip out during conversation,
마치 마음이 맞는 사람이라도
찾고 있다는 듯이
maybe you find someone like-minded.
그래, 하지만 미끼를 무는 녀석이나
용의자는 찾을 수 없었어
Yeah, didn't get any takers
or find any suspects.
It's pretty thin.
정말 미꾸라지 같은 녀석이야
런웨이의 모델들이 더 미꾸라지 같죠
Runway-model thin.
어쩌면 녀석을 찾을지도 몰라요
But we may be able to get her a sandwich.
- 단서라도 잡은거야?
- 네
You have a lead?
Yes.
터키쉬 하모니를 국가정보시스템에서
찾아보게 했죠
We ran a search on the national database
for Turkish Harmony.
You actually got a hit.
제대로 단서를 잡은 모양인데
이틀 전에 뉴저지에서 식수 운반 차량이
도난 당한 사건이 있었어요
Two days ago, a water delivery
truck was stolen in Jersey.
관할 경찰관들이 흔히 하듯이
DNA랑 섬유샘플을 채취하고 있었는데
When the locals did their sweep
for the usual DNA and fiber samples,
바닥에서 담배 조각들을 발견한거예요
they also picked up a few flakes
of the tobacco from the floor.
식수 운반 차량에서?
A water delivery truck?
- 그러게요, 이상하지 않아요?
- 응
I know, it's strange, right?
Yeah.
어때요?
Any thoughts?
트럭을 조사해 보자
Yeah. Check out the truck.
근데 그게 뉴저지에 있다면
좀 어려운 일이겠는걸
But that's hard to do when it's in Jersey.
네가 신경이나 쓰고 있는지 모르겠지만
난 증거물 보관소에서 일하고
In case you haven't
noticed, I'm in evidence,
and you've got a radius again.
넌 반경내에서만 움직여야 하잖아
맞아요, 트럭을 찾아갈 순 없겠죠
Yeah, right. We can't go to the truck.
그래서 다이애나가 우릴 위해
전화를 몇 통화 해줬죠
So, Diana made a few phone calls for us.
우리 앞으로 트럭이 배달왔네요
Had the truck delivered to us.
여긴 직장이니까 상관 없는거죠
You're in evidence now.
저걸 살펴본다고 해서 손해볼 건 없잖아요?
There's no harm in taking a look, is there?
Come on.
보고서에 의하면 발견되고 나서
곧 바로 견인 돼 왔군
According to the report,
the truck was hauled in
directly after it was found.
즉 마지막으로 운전했던 사람이
바로 범인이란 뜻이겠네요
Meaning the last person to drive it
was the same person who stole it.
그래 들어가서 추론해 보는거야
용의자의 신체적 특징이라던지 말야
All right, we get inside,
maybe we can deduce
the physical characteristics
of the suspect --
적어도 키 정돈 알아내겠지
height at least.
그걸 가지고 위장근무에서 얻어낸
직원 자료랑 비교해 보는 거예요
Yeah, we get that, we
can cross-reference it
against the list of bank employees
from your undercover stint.
근데 문제는 지난 번에 철사를
이용해 차에 시동을 걸었다는 거야
Yeah. One problem -- the
truck was hot-wired.
We don't have access to keys.
열쇠를 얻을 방법이 없어
언제부터 제가 열쇠가 필요했죠?
Since when do I need keys?
필요없지
You don't.
좋았어요, 저기에 고정시키세요
All right, just keep
that wedged right there.
Not too hard.
너무 세게 하진 마시고요
Be careful. This is still evidence.
조심해, 여전히 증거품이라고
A little more room.
좀 더 공간이 필요해요
알았어
Yep.
Got it.
좋았어
어떤 녀석이었을까요?
What's the story?
내가 190.5cm 이고 좌석이
운전대랑 너무 가까이 있어
I'm 6'2", and this seat
is way too close to the steering wheel.
고로 용의자는 182가 안넘을거야
So, I'm guessing that our
suspect is well under 6'.
175에서 178 정도가 최고겠어
Maybe 5'9", 5'10" at the most.
뭐가 있어?
What do you have?
보고서에 의하면 생수 세 통이
없어졌다고 하던데요
Well, according to the report,
there were three water bottles missing.
어딘가로 배달했었겠지
Yeah. He delivered them somewhere.
Well, maybe.
그럴지도요
어떻게 옮겨졌는지에 더 관심이 가네요
I'm more interested in how they were moved.
- 여깄네요
- 손수레를 사용했군
There we go. Use the hand truck.
그 말은 녀석이 손수 트럭까지
운반을 했고
Which he would have had to bring back
to the truck himself...
묶어놨단 뜻이겠죠
And tie up.
왼쪽이 위로 가있어요
Left over right.
용의자는 왼손잡이야
Left over right. Our
suspect is left-handed.
- 맞아요
- 좋았어
Yep.
Okay.
키는 175 정도의 왼손잡이 이면서
때때로 담배를 피우는 녀석을 찾아보자
We're on the lookout for a 5'9" lefty
who enjoys the occasional smoke.
시작이네요
It's a start.
얼마나 거기서
더 버틸 수 있을지 모르겠어
I do not know how much longer
I can work in evidence.
그저 핸드폰을 분류해서 상자에 채우고
Just cataloging phones
and boxing up evidence
엄청난 서류 작업이나 하고 말야
and filing endless paperwork.
그 사람들은 자기가 얼마나 범죄자들을
잡아 냈는지 알기는 하는거야?
Do they know how many criminals
you've taken off the street?
닐은 잡아넣지 않았잖아
아무래도 그게 문제 인것 같아
I think it's the one I left on the street
that's the problem.
Give me a second.
잠깐만
Speak of the devil.
호랑이도 제 말하면 온다더니
닐, 늦었네
Neal, it's late.
그래, 어서 들어오렴
Sure. Come on in.
찾았어요
We got him.
뭐라고?
What?
안녕하세요, 엘리자베스
Oh, hey, Elizabeth.
안녕, 잡담은 됐고
Hey. Enough chit-chat.
누군데?
Who is it?
All right.
교통국 자료에 따르면 요원님
전 동료들 중에 178에서 182는 7명
DMV records show that seven of
your old bank "co-workers"
are between 5'10" and 6',
but only one is a lefty.
하지만 왼손잡이는 단 한명이죠
어떻게 알았어?
교통국에서 물어보진 않았을 테고
How do you know?
DMV doesn't ask.
서명이죠
The signature.
왼손잡이인 사람들이 이름을 사인 할 땐
자주 손바닥으로 잉크를 번지게 하거든요
When left-handed people sign their name,
their palms often smudge the ink.
데이비드 쿡
David Cook.
- 10년이 지나서야 용의자를 발견했군
- 네
- After 10 years, I have a suspect.
- Yeah.
이제 녀석이 다음 목표를 어디로 할지
알아낼 시간이 일주일도 안남았어요
And now we have less than a week
to figure out where he's gonna strike next.
Do you recognize him?
알아보시겠어요?
David Cook was a bank teller
I met while undercover.
데이비드 쿡은 창구 직원이었어
잠입수사 할 때 만났었지
I didn't like him.
좋아하진 않았어
Any particular reason?
특별한 이유라도 있었어요?
He was a Mets fan.
뉴욕 메츠 편이었거든
Oh.
Me being a die-hard Yankee fan,
난 뉴욕양키즈 골수 팬이었으니
이걸 가지고 몇 번이나 부딪혔었지
we went at it a few times.
Type-"A" kind of guy?
경쟁심이 강한 사람이었나봐요?
Yeah.
응
What does he want with a
water delivery truck?
식수 운반 차량으로
뭘 하려고 한 걸까요?
The bureau will figure it out.
부서에서 알아내겠지
No, no, no, no. We have come this close
왜 그래요, 요원님 덕에
이렇게 접근 할 수 있었다고요
because of you, Peter.
Yeah, and if you need any
advice, I'm always around.
그래, 내 조언이 필요하다면
언제든지 찾아와
Great. I want some advice.
좋아요, 조언이 필요해요
How do we catch Cook?
어떻게 하면 쿡을 잡을수 있을까요
Competition, like I said.
내가 말했듯이 경쟁이야
He never delegated any
of his work at the bank,
은행에서 자기 업무는 죽어도
남한테 맡기지 않았어
like he had to do it himself.
마치 자기만 이 일을 해야만
한다는 것 처럼 말야
Oh, a control freak.
자기 뜻대로만 하려는 녀석이네
He never mentioned family.
자기 가족얘기는 단 한번도 한적없어
Probably avoids emotional connections.
아마 감정적인 교류는 피하고 싶겠지
That makes it tough to get to him.
그래서 녀석을 잡기 힘들었던 거군요
Cook did have routines.
쿡은 녀석만의 패턴이 있었어
He hit the gym every day,
was always on time to work,
매일 체육관에 가, 출근에 늦는 법이 없고
and he always took his
lunch at the same deli.
점심을 매번 같은 곳에서 사먹어
Creature of habit.
Yeah.
- 습관의 표본이네요
- 응
So find his latest habits.
그러니 녀석의 최근 습관을 찾아봐
Ask Hughes to get
'round-the-clock eyes on him.
휴즈요원님께 녀석을 24시간
감시해야 한다고 말씀드려
We're gonna catch this guy.
이 녀석 잡고 말거예요
Keep me posted.
계속 알려줘
You know where you can find me.
날 어디서 찾을지는 알고 있지
All right!
그럼요!
Hey.
그래
Good news.
좋은 뉴스에요
Hughes approved your idea
for surveillance on Cook.
휴즈요원님이 쿡에 대한 감시를
승인하셨어요
We already got eyes on him.
물론 이미 감시에 들어갔었지만요
He's got a weekly squash game
at the Soho health club.
소호에 있는 헬스클럽에서
매주 스쿼시 게임을 한데요
I didn't peg him for a squash guy.
녀석이 스쿼시를 치는 사람일줄은
생각도 못했는데
Well, you haven't seen him in 10 years.
10년이나 못봤으니까요
Apparently he traded his love of the Mets
분명히 자신의 메츠를 향한 열정을
좀 더 고급스런 스포츠로 전향했나봐요
for a more upscale sport.
I like the guy even less now.
정말 사랑스런 녀석이군
Nobody trades up from baseball.
야구를 배신하다니
Is that a private call, Burke?
사적인 통화중인가, 버크?
I-it'll be done in a second.
금방 끊겠습니다
Second's up!
그럴 시간 없어!
The only phone I want to see in your hand
자네 손에 핸드폰이 쥐어지는 게
허락되는 건
is the one you're filing away.
You got it?
오직 핸드폰 분류하고 있을 때 뿐이야
알아 듣겠나?
I got to go.
그만 끊을게
I'll keep you posted.
계속 연락드릴게요
Thank you.
What are you doing?
뭐하는거야?
Oh...nothing.
That's the problem.
아무것도, 그게 문제야
Then what are you waiting for?
Huh?
그럼 뭘 기다리는거야? 응?
Go out there.
나가봐
Well, nice as that sounds,
글쎄, 그러고야 싶지
I'm on very strict orders now.
지금은 아주 고약한 명령을 따르는 중이라
Yes, you're off-duty, but
you still have a badge.
자기가 일선에선 물러났다고 해도
여전히 FBI라고
Well, technically, yes.
뭐, 그렇기야 하지만
What rule would you be breaking?
규칙이라도 어겨야 하는 일이야?
None of them yet, but
this case -- I got to --
아직까진 안 그랬지만
이번 사건은...
Honey, I know how important
this is for you.
여보, 이게 얼마나 자기한테
중요한 사건이란 거 알아
So go be a part of it.
가서 해야할 일을 해
I want to.
나야 그러고 싶지
I know.
So see it through.
이해해, 그러니 끝을 봐
You're an FBI agent, Peter Burke.
자긴 FBI요원이야, 피터 버크
Go get your job back.
자기 일을 되찾아와
Okay, we're live.
좋았어, 연결됐어요
Cook should be inside any minute now.
쿡이 몇 분내로 들어올 거예요
Who are you texting?
누구랑 문자해요?
Peter. I'm keeping him posted.
요원님요, 계속 보고 중이에요
Thanks for the update.
업데이트 고마워
What are you doing here?
여기서 뭐하세요?
Was out for a walk and
saw a suspicious van.
산책 나왔는데 수상쩍은 밴을 봤거든
Wanted to know if there was
안에서 불법행위가 있지 않을까 싶어
확인을 하려던 것 뿐이야
any illegal activity going on inside.
Just a convict and an
FBI agent watching TV.
그저 재소자랑 FBI요원이 TV보고 있어요
Get in here.
들어오세요
Anything decent on the tube?
괜찮은 것 좀 건졌어?
We're wired into the health
club's closed-circuit cameras.
헬스클럽의 폐쇄 회로 카메라에
접속됐어요
Only blind spots are the locker rooms.
유일한 사각지대는 탈의실 뿐이에요
That's him.
저깄네
Oh, you catch that?
방금 보셨어요?
He's being protective of that bag.
뭔가 보호해야 할 만한게 있나본데
Curious what's inside?
안에 뭐가 있는지 궁금하신거죠?
Oh, I'd be lying if I said no.
아니라면 거짓말이겠지
How about we find out?
어떻게 알아내죠?
Wouldn't it be nice
'쿡이 옛날 친구 피터 모리스를
우연히 만나게 된다면'은 어때요?
if Cook ran into his old
friend Peter Morris?
No. Unh-unh.
안돼
What? You were busted for larceny.
왜요? 모리스는 절도죄로 체포됐었고
We're about to bust him for larceny.
우린 쿡을 막 절도죄로
잡으려는 참이잖아요
You two have a lot to talk about.
나눌 말씀이 많을 것 같은데요
What would I even say to him?
녀석한테 뭐라고 말을 걸어야 하는데?
You can ask him if he's stolen
"최근에 식수 운반 트럭 훔치지
않았어?" 라고 물어보세요
any water delivery trucks lately.
Good. Subtle.
거참, 영리하네
Or... "How about a game?"
아니면..."게임 한판 할래?"
It's been a while since I played squash.
스쿼시 친 적 오래됐어
Well, I hear it's like riding a bike.
한번 배운건 절대 잊어먹지 않는 법이래요
From who?
누가 그래?
I'm sure that someone... said that once.
누구한테 들었냐면...
그걸 말해줬던 사람한테서요
Yeah, I'm sure.
어련하시겠어
I'd need some workout gear.
운동용품이 필요하겠어
Shouldn't be a problem.
문제없죠
This shirt's kind of itchy.
이 셔츠 왜 이렇게 간지러워
It was all the pro shop had.
전문 스포츠 용품점에서 골랐어요
Next time I spend 90 bucks
for a pair of sweats,
다음엔 내가 돈 더 주고라도 사야겠어
I'd better get a free TV with them.
그러면 사은품으로 TV라도 줄지도
Come on, this place is nice.
여기 물 좋은데요
In fact, I'm thinking of joining.
저도 함께 운동하고 싶어지네요
You get plenty of exercise.
도망 다니느라 충분히 했을텐데
It has its benefits.
그것도 그것 나름대로의 장점이 있어요
그래 검찰로 부터 멀리
달아나기 운동이라고 해야하나
Yeah. So does flight from prosecution.
Good cardio.
특히 심장에 좋아요
Bring it!
Yeah!
이리로 와!
좋았어!
Uh-oh. He's not messing around.
느긋한 성격은 아닌가봐요
No, I told you -- Cook's competitive.
응, 말했듯이 쿡은 경쟁심이 강해
Good. Use that to keep him busy.
좋아요, 그 점을 이용해서
녀석의 시선을 끌어줘요
When you catch up, ask
him how's he's doing.
요즘엔 어떻게 지내는 지 물어보세요
Whatever he says,
녀석이 어떻게 말하던지
casually imply you're
doing a little better.
내가 더 잘 살고 있다는 걸
은연중에 내비쳐 주세요
If he's making money, you're
making a little more.
돈을 좀 모으고 있다면
좀 더 모으고 있다는 식이죠
If he drives a Beemer, you drive a Ferrari.
BMW를 소유하고 있다고 하면
페라리 있다고 하세요
You want me to challenge him.
자극시키길 바라는 구나
Yeah, he'll try to one-up you.
어떻게든 하나라도 앞서고 싶어 할 걸요
자기가 자기 스스로를 옭아맬거예요
He won't be able to help himself.
You'll be on that court in no time.
어서 저기 코트에 합류하세요
Then what?
그리고 나선?
Try not to lose too fast. Good luck.
너무 빨리 지지만 마세요
행운을 빌어요
I'm telling you -- you got to
work on your backhand, man.
정말 백핸드 연습 좀 했나본데
You're quick, but, uh...
ground strokes, baby.
정말 빨랐어, 근데 바운드 된
공 처리하는 연습은 더해야 겠더라
Better luck next time, friend.
다음엔 더 잘해보자고, 친구
Dave? Dave Cook?
데이브? 데이브 쿡?
Peter Morris. We worked together.
피터 모리스야, 같이 일했었잖아
Region Financial. Been a while.
리전 파이낸셜! 오랜만이네
Yeah. Yeah. How you been?
그러게, 어떻게 지냈어?
Great. Yourself?
훌륭하지, 자넨?
Great. Actually, beyond great.
훌륭해, 실은 엄청 훌륭해
I didn't know you played.
스쿼시 치는 줄은 몰랐네
Yeah, when I can get a game.
응, 장소가 마땅치가 않네
I've still got the court.
내가 쓰던 코트 아직 예약되어 있어
Terrific.
그거 좋지
Been a while since I left the bank.
- 은행을 떠나고 나서 참 오랜만이야
- 그 뒤로 뭐하고 지냈어?
What have you been doing since?
I was gonna ask you the same.
사실 내가 물어보고 싶었던 말인데
Started my own little business --
내 비즈니스 부터 소개하자면
작게나마 수출입을 하고 있지
import/export trade.
Profitable.
짭짤하더라고
Funny. I started my own business, too.
재밌네, 나도 내 사업을 시작했는데 말야
Small financial firm.
소규모의 금융회사야
Financial firm?
금융회사?
Last time I saw you, you
were mopping floors!
마지막으로 자넬 봤을 때
잡일이나 했던 것 같은데
Hard to get hired when you got a record.
전과가 있으니 채용되긴 어렵더라고
That's some initiative.
그것 참 대단하네
You could say I took some
time out, educated myself.
좀 쉬거나 더 연습하고 오라고
말하고 싶겠지
I tell you what, since
we're both doing so well,
아무래도 둘다 꽤 치는 것 같은데
친목 도모겸 내기 어때?
how about a little friendly wager?
Okay.
좋지
Winner takes a grand from the loser?
지는 사람이 천 달러 내기
A grand?
천 달러?
That a problem?
문제있나?
No, no. But let's make it 2.
아니, 2천 달러로 하지
2?
2천?
Not 3?
3천은?
You're right. Let's make it an even 5.
좋아, 딱 5천으로 하지
You're on.
시작하지
All right.
그래
Hidden camera?
몰래 카메라?
Water-cooler talk.
냉수기 앞에서의 대화라
You all right?
괜찮아?
Yeah, I'm fine.
응, 괜찮아
Come on. Move.
조금 비켜주면 좋겠는데
My shoulder's acting up.
어깨 쪽 질병이 재발한 것 같아
I've got an ice pack in the locker room.
탈의실 가서 얼음찜질좀 해야겠어
Is that your rotator cuff?
어깨 근육에 문제있는거야?
Eh, yeah. I pulled it before.
It's not a problem.
예전에 어깨가 빠졌었거든
큰 문제는 아냐
You should be careful, much more careful!
조심해야지, 정말 조심해야돼!
Where's your locker?
자네 락커는 어딨어?
It's just around here. Come on.
바로 이 근처야
You sure you don't want me to get someone
정말 내가 어깨 한번 살펴봐 주지
않아도 되겠어?
to take a look at that shoulder?
What'd I tell you? It's not a problem.
왜 그러는건데? 심각한거 아니래도
Shame we didn't get to finish.
결판을 내지 못해 아쉽네
Yeah. Yeah, it is.
그러게, 아쉬워
You know, I'm always up for round 2.
난 언제나 2라운드 부터
몸이 풀리는데 말야
That was barely a round 1.
1라운드도 버티기 힘들어 보이던데
Can't find that pack?
아이스팩 못 찾았어?
Oh, it's probably in my bag.
아마 가방안에 있을 거야
You don't want to do that.
그러지 않는게 좋을거야
I just remembered --
어디서 봤는데
you're supposed to use heat on
an injury like that, not ice.
그런 부상에는 얼음찜질 보다는
핫팩으로 지지는게 좋다더라
Yeah, I read it somewhere. Heat. Heat.
- 나도 어디선가 본 것 같아
- 뜨겁게, 뜨겁게
Well, I don't have a heat pack.
근데 가지고 있는 핫팩이 없어서 말야
Yeah, well, that's fine.
뭐 그래도 상관없어
They've got them in the pro shop.
스포츠 용품점에 가면 있으니까
나가는 길에 살 수 있을거야
You can get one on the way out.
Heat.
뜨겁게
Hey! You've got green dots in your locker.
이봐! 자네 라커에 그린닷츠가 있네!
Can I borrow one? I'm always out.
하나 빌려도 될까?
언제나 다 써버리고 말지
Keep it.
가져
Thanks.
고마워
As a reminder that we have
some unfinished business.
아직 끝내지 못한 승부가
있단 걸 잊지 마
I'm around for a rematch anytime you want.
네가 원하면 언제든 준비가 되있지
Yeah, you better be good for it.
그래, 이번 보단 잘하겠지
Oh, believe me, once I start something,
걱정마, 뭔가를 시작하기만 하면
끝장을 보는 성격이니까
I always like to see it through.
What was so fascinating
뭐가 그렇게 재밌어서 날 곤란하게
만들었던 거야?
you had to force me into
a game of hot potato?
Cook has a live feed running on his PDA.
녀석의 PDA가 실시간으로
어딘가를 감시하고 있었어요
Micro camera with a hidden transmitter.
송신기가 부착된 몰래 카메라에요
Guess where it was hidden.
어디에 숨겨져 있던 건지 맞춰보세요
Inside the water cooler.
냉수기 안에 있었어요
That explains the stolen truck.
왜 그 트럭을 훔쳤는지 설명이 되네
He used it to impersonate a delivery man
트럭으로 배달원 행세를 하고
어딘가에 카메라를 심어놨겠지
and plant the camera somewhere.
Yeah, that's smart.
똑똑해요
The live feed allows him to
study his marks in real time.
실시간 영상으로 목표물에 대해
일거수 일투족을 알 수 있잖아요
What did you see?
뭘 봤어?
A diamond shop. I didn't get the name.
다이아몬드 상점이에요
이름은 알아내지 못했어요
But I got a close-enough look
to sketch out the floor plan.
하지만 평면도를 그릴 만큼은
충분히 살펴봤죠
I'm gonna go back to the
office and draw one up.
부서로 돌아가서 그려야 겠어요
Peter and I will start narrowing
targets from his place.
요원님과 저는 타겟을 좁혀볼게요
You can coordinate with me from the office.
사무실에 가서 연락줘요
Six diamond stores in Manhattan
'램의 생수'를 시켜먹는 상점이
멘하탄에 여섯 군데 있어요
are supplied by Ram's Water Delivery.
Cook could hit one of these any second now.
녀석은 지금이라도
이 중에 하나를 털 수 있단거지
Then he disappears again.
그러고 나면 다시 사라지겠지
Neal, did you e-mail the sketch?
Yeah. Sent.
- 닐, 스케치 이메일로 보냈어요?
- 네, 보냈어요
Making any progress?
진척이라도?
We're getting somewhere. Thanks, honey.
대략적으로 짐작중이야
고마워, 자기
Ah, don't tell me that.
That doesn't sound good.
- 아, 그게 무슨 말이에요
- 무슨 일이지
Jones, what's up?
존스, 무슨 일이야?
Okay. Keep searching.
알겠습니다, 계속 찾아봐주세요
Cook just ducked surveillance.
쿡이 방금 감시망을 빠져나갔어요
Team one lost him in the
subway about 15 minutes ago,
1팀이 지하철에서 15분 전에
그를 놓쳤다고 해요
but they said it looked like
he was trying to go dark.
마지 범죄를 저지르러 갈 것
처럼 보였다는 거예요
He's pulling the job.
녀석이 행동을 개시한거예요
This is happening tonight.
오늘 밤에 훔치려는거겠지
All right, we need to figure this out now.
좋아, 이곳이 당장 어디인지 알아내자
You guys have that list?
상점 목록 가지고 있어?
Yeah, I got it.
네, 있어요
All right, well, we can cross off Toback's.
토박이란 가게는 지워도 될 것 같아요
Christie and I went ring shopping there,
크리스티랑 반지를 사러 갔었는데
저런 모습이 아니었거든요
and this isn't what it looked like.
Plus, their security system is top-notch.
더불어 그 쪽 보안은 최상이었어요
You scoped out their security?
반지사러 가서 보안점검하고 왔어?
Ring shopping's not really my thing.
반지사는건 제 적성에 안 맞더라고요
All right, you can also cross off Davis,
좋아요, 다비스도 아니에요
Smith Brothers, and Solitaire and Sons.
스미스 형제들, 솔리테리와 손즈도
지워주시고요
I'd recognize the interiors.
인테리어가 기억나거든요
Because you cased them out?
털려고 계획했었나보지?
Ring shopping's not really my thing.
반지 '사는건' 적성에 안맞아서요
All right, that leaves us with two --
그럼 두 곳이 남는군
Midtown Jewelry Appraisers
and Crowder Diamonds.
미드타운 보석 감정원이랑
크라우더 다이아몬즈
That's Crowder Diamonds.
그럼 크라운드 다이아몬즈 겠네
I took a client to Midtown
Jewelers last month.
지난 달에 미드타운 쥬얼리에
고객이 있었거든
They have two long cases of merchandise.
아주 긴 진열장이 두 개 있었어
No vault in sight.
Definitely not like that.
금고가 저렇게 나와있지도 않았고
분명히 저런 모습은 아니야
Honey, I have to --
자기, 정말...
You got to go. Good luck.
어서 가야지, 행운을 빌어
I'll let the teams know the target.
팀에 목표상점을 알려주겠습니다
Hopefully we can intercept.
우리가 잡았으면 좋겠네요
Yeah, we're on our way.
알았어, 우리도 출발할게
You ride separate. I'll follow.
따로 가지, 따라 갈게
I'm just an observer.
난 그저 관찰자일 뿐이니까
Just give me a call if
anything turns up, okay?
사소한 거라도 발견하면
나한테 전화줘요, 알았죠?
What happened?
무슨일이 있던거야?
Place was hit 20 minutes ago.
20분 전에 도둑을 맞았어요
No sign of Cook?
쿡의 흔적은?
Preliminary forensics shows a
clean crime scene, so far.
초기 수사에선 발견한 건
없다고 하네요, 지금까진요
And it'll stay that way.
그리고 계속 발견 못하겠지
All right. Stay here.
여기 있어
Keep me posted.
Peter.
- 계속 알려줘
- 피터
I can't be here.
여기 있을 순 없어
I shouldn't have come in the first place.
애초에 오지 말았어야 했어
좋아!
Yes!
It's all in the strategy, my friends.
다 내 계획이었다고, 친구들
I'm gonna sit this round out,
이번 판은 쉴게
다른 사람도 돈을 좀 따야지
let someone else win some tugriks.
Back so soon?
일찍왔네?
Well, no man is an island.
글쎄, 섬에만 있을 인물은 아니잖아
And you're clean-shaven.
깨끗하게 면도했네
You have retired from retirement.
은퇴생활에서 은퇴한거구나
I can come and go as I please.
난 내 의지대로 움직일 수 있는 사람이라고
Plus, as the man behind many a curtain,
덧붙여서, 베일에 둘러쌓인 인물로서
I found myself...
나 스스로를...
lacking a reliable... front.
신뢰할 수 없는 사람이라 할 수 있지...
겉으로는 말이지
So you're saying I'm your front man?
그러니 내가 네 얼굴마담이라?
Good partnerships are hard to find.
훌륭한 파트너 쉽은 찾기 어렵거든
Who are your friends?
저 친구들은 누구야?
Oh, just some fellow travelers
우리가 라이프라 부르는 이번 여행의
동료들 이야
on this journey we call life.
Yeah, they like my ice wines.
저 사람들이 내 아이스와인을 좋아하나봐
Well, they are from colder climes.
우리보다 더 추은 지방에서 왔으니까
What's the game?
무슨 게임이야?
No idea, but I'm very good at it.
전혀 모르겠어
근데 나 완전 잘하는거 있지
Oh, deal me in.
나도 껴줘
The treasure?
보물은?
It's safe. How's the Suit?
안전해, 요원님은?
I take it he returned
from our balmy tropics
우리가 있던 살기 좋은 동네에서
끔찍한 곳으로 돌아가셨겠지?
to much harsher weather?
He's been relegated to the
bureau's storage warehouse.
요원님은 증거물 보관창고로 좌천되셨어
Endless cages filled with contraband?
끝도 없이 밀수품이 가득찬 그 곳?
It's not as nice as it sounds.
그리 좋은 곳은 아냐
He's stuck itemizing cargo
crates of stolen cellphones.
핸드폰 장물들을 창고에
분류 시키는 작업에 치여 살고 계셔
It's my fault he's in this spot.
그 분이 그곳에 계신건 내 잘못이야
I need to get him out of it.
그러니 꺼내드리고 싶어
Solving this latest case will help.
이 사건을 해결하는게 도움이 될 거야
Oh, what's involved? Stolen diamonds.
- 무슨 일인데?
- 다이아몬드 절도
We had a suspect, but
he's gone underground.
용의자가 있었는데 사라져 버렸어
Has he liquidated yet?
아직 현금으로 바꾸진 않았고?
By the time the FBI finds his fence,
녀석의 장물아비를 찾는 순간
그 보석들은 자취를 감출거야
those gems will be long gone.
Well, who needs the fuzz when you have me?
나랑 있으면서 뭔 걱정이야
It's good to have you back.
네가 돌아와서 기뻐
닐, 무슨 일이야?
Neal. What's going on?
쿡에 관련된 거예요
It's about Cook.
Figured.
우리가 간과한건 없는지
모든 증거를 검토하고 있는 중이야
I'm going over all the evidence,
trying to find something
we might have overlooked.
그러실 필요 없어요
That won't be necessary.
요원님이 녀석을 잡게
도울 방법이 생각났거든요
I've got an idea that
will help you catch him.
내가 아니라 FBI를 돕는거야
You mean help the bureau catch him.
아니요, 이번 건은 요원님거예요
No. It has to be you and you alone.
제 방법이 통하려면 이 길뿐이에요
It's the only way my plan works.
이제 더 이상 내 사건이 아니야
This is not my assignment anymore.
명령을 어길 순 없어
I can't disobey orders.
끝까지 들으셨어야죠
직접 나서실 필요는 없어요
Well, that's the best part.
You don't have to.
녀석을 잡기 위해 또 5년을 기다리실래요
Look, Peter, we can wait another
five years to catch this guy,
아니면 내일 잡을 수도 있어요
or we can take him down tomorrow.
요원님한테 달렸어요
It's your call.
계획이 뭔데?
What's the plan?
이 여자가 팀의 장물아비에요
리나 옥스
This is Cook's fence -- Rina Oaks.
정보원들을 통해서 이 여자를
추척하는 데 성공해냈죠
I was able to track her down
using a reliable street contact.
그 정보원이 내가 아는 사람인가?
Mm. Do I know any of these
"reliable street contacts"?
요원님이 그렇게 선호할 만한
사람은 아닐거예요
You'd probably prefer not to.
그러겠지
I'm sure.
쿡은 경쟁심이 강해요
Cook is a competitive guy.
우리가 녀석의 경쟁심을 자극해서
What if we give him a little competition
제발로 우리 앞에
나타나게 해보면 어떨까요?
that puts him directly in our sights?
계속해봐
I'm listening.
피터 모리스 위장은 완벽하잖아요
Your cover as Peter Morris is perfect.
그가 이미 모리스를 전과자로
알고 있으니까
He already thinks you're
a convicted criminal.
요원님이 녀석의 연락책들에게
접선 한다면 어떤 반응을 보일까요?
What if you, uh, discovered
one of his contacts in the underworld?
리나 같은 사람 말이지?
Someone like Rina?
만약 놈의 장물아비와 접촉해서
더 나은 조건을 제시한다는 것을
If we can convince Cook
you found out about his fence and
are making a better offer...
녀석이 알게 한다면
녀석을 물 밖으로 꺼내겠지
We draw him out.
맞아요
Exactly.
내가 거래를 하고 있을 때
녀석이 난입할테고
He barges in when I'm making the deal.
사람들을 배치해 둘 다 체포한다면
We have people in place
to bring them both down.
부서에서는 두 마리의 토끼를 잡고
The bureau gets a double win,
요원님은 축하를 받으며
돌아가시게 되는 거죠
and you're back in their good graces.
좋은 생각인걸
It's a nice idea.
근데 내일 아침 9시까지
보고서를 써야 하거든
But I have to report to
evidence at 9:00 A.M. tomorrow.
다행히 제가 리나와의 약속을
8시로 잡아놨어요
Good thing I made your
appointment with Rina for 8:00.
알았어, 이제 내가 적당한 경쟁자라고
리나가 확신할 수 있게
All right. We'd need real stones
to convince Rina that I am
a legitimate competition.
진짜 보석이 필요하겠는걸
안 훔쳤어요, 준씨의 호의에요
I didn't steal them. Courtesy of June.
카나리는 50만 달러 정도이고
The canary is worth half a million.
로얄 블루도 그 정도해요
The royal blue is worth
another half million.
분홍색이 70만 달러죠
And the pink's worth $700,000.
와우, 준씨 한테 어떻게...
Wow. I had no idea June --
네, 괜찮으시데요
Yeah, she does okay.
이 두 녀석이 120만 달러는 되는거죠
So these two make up an additional 1.2.
하지만 쿡은 4백만이 넘는 보석이 있어
But Cook has now over $4 million.
얘네가 요원님을 쿡보다
더 매력적으로 보이게 해줄거예요
Well, these should make you
more appealing than Cook.
그걸로 유리는 못 자를거예요
They won't cut glass.
가짜야?
Knock-offs?
리나가 이걸 본다면
가짜란 걸 알아챌거야
The second Rina sees them,
she's gonna know they're fake.
감정도 못할거예요
She won't get to them.
그저 쿡이 가게에 나타날 수 있게
시간이나 넉넉히 끌어주세요
All you have to do is buy enough time
to make sure Cook crosses
town and arrives at the shop.
그때까지 리나한테 가짜보석이
진짜로 보이게 하는 법만 공부하세요
Meanwhile, you'll make
sure Rina only studies
the diamonds that are true.
어떻게?
How?
하나만 골라보세요, 아무거나요
Pick one of those up. Any one.
이제 돌려보세요
Now turn it over.
어떻게 이걸 선택할줄 알았어?
How did you do that?
From the minute you walked in here,
여기 들어오시는 순간 부터 미묘하게
요원님 마음을 조종하고 있었어요
I've been subtly steering your mind
그 로얄 블루 다이아몬드에
집중하시도록 말이죠
to focus on that royal blue diamond.
그럴리가, 어떻게 한건지 알려줘
No, come on. Tell me how you did this.
안돼요, 한번에 하나씩 이에요
No, no. One thing at a time.
하실거예요?
Are you in?
하지
I'm in.
지금 생각중인 계획은
세 파트로 되어 있어요
What I'm proposing is a three-part plan.
파트 1 부터 시작하죠
So let's start with part one.
가장 우선순위로는 쿡을
표면위로 나오게 하는 거예요
The first thing we have
to do is draw Cook out.
리나의 가게에 들어서는 순간 부터
시작하는 거예요
And that starts the minute you
walk through Rina's door.
피터 모리스 입니다
Peter Morris.
네, 메세지 받았어요
Yes, I got your message.
처음엔 리나가 신뢰하지 않을거예요
Rina won't trust you at first.
신원조회를 위해 이것 저것
물어볼텐데
She's gonna ask you for a reference,
보증인에게 전화를 걸고 싶다고 하세요
so you tell her you want
to call a mutual friend.
데이비드 쿡이요
그가 저를 보증해 줄겁니다
David Cook. He can vouch for me.
리나, 내일 만나기로 했잖아
Rina. We don't meet until tomorrow.
누구?
Who?
피터 모리스, 그가 당신을 안다던데?
Peter Morris. Says he knows you?
그 녀석이 대체 거기서 뭐하는거야?
What the hell is he doing there?
거래를 하시자네
Making me an offer.
안돼, 그러지마
No, no, no. No, no. Hey, hey.
그 녀석이랑 상종도 하지마
No, you know what? You stay away from him.
내 돈에 얼씬도 하게 하지 말라고!
You keep him away from my money!
- 내 돈이지
- 나랑 약속했잖아
You mean my money. I thought we had a deal?
무슨 말 하려는 건지는 알겠어
I hear what you're saying.
아니, 전혀 이해 못하는 것 같은데
No, I don't think that you do.
모리스는 거짓말쟁이에
유명한 도둑이야
Morris is a liar and a known thief.
믿으면 안돼!
You don't trust him!
본인은 아니신가요, 쿡씨
Glass houses, Mr. Cook.
내 수중에 엄청난 돈이 있다는 것만
알아줬으면 좋겠어
You understand I only have
so much cash on-hand.
코드명 "더 나은 제안을 해봐"
Code for, "make me a better offer."
쿡은 내 이름을 듣는 것만 해도
달가워 하지 않을거야
Cook won't be happy to hear my name.
그게 핵심인걸요
Well, that's the whole point.
요원님이 경쟁을 걸어왔다고 생각할거예요
그게 녀석의 참을성을 터뜨리는거죠
He'll think you're competing.
It'll push his buttons.
And Rina is smart enough
그리고 리나는 경쟁을 붙이는 게
유리하다고 판단할 만큼 똑똑하죠
to know a good competition
when she sees it.
기다려, 곧 갈게
Hang on. I'm on my way to you.
자 이제 파트 2로 넘어가죠
Now we'll move on to phase two --
쿡이 도착할 때까지
리나를 잘 묶어 두세요
keeping Rina around until Cook arrives.
저희는 리나가 보석을 감정할
시간을 벌고 있을게요
We'll buy our time making
Rina appraise the gems --
제대로 된 보석 말이죠
the right gems.
어떻게 블루로얄을 고르게 했는지
말해 줄 때가 온 것 같은데
This is where you tell me
how you got me to pick the blue stone.
더 나은게 있어요, 어떻게 하실수
있는지에 대해 알려드릴게요
Better. This is where I teach
you how to do it yourself.
파란색 넥타이를 매는 것이
블루로얄을 고르게 하는 첫 단추죠
I began pushing you toward the blue diamond
by wearing a blue tie, which
you'll also be wearing.
요원님 역시 파란색 넥타이를
매시게 될 거예요
그러고 나서 미묘한 행동들을
하기 시작했죠
Then I started making subtle gestures --
넥타이를 고쳐 맨다든가
주름을 폈죠
adjusting my tie, smoothing it out,
색깔에 집중하시게 하는 거예요
drawing your attention to the color.
그 정도야 할 수 있지
I can do that.
다음엔 행커칩을 계속 만지작
거리는 거예요, 역시 파란색이죠
Next I fiddle with my
handkerchief, also blue.
인상적이에요, 어떻게 구하셨어요?
Impressive. And how did you come by these?
상담이나 받자고 내놓은게 아니에요
감정이나 해주세요
That's not up for discussion.
Shall we get started?
똑똑한 전략이야
Clever tactic.
헌데 그녀가 블루로얄을
감정하고 나서는 어떻게?
But once she's done looking
at the blue diamond --
자극을 시킬만한 단어들로
카나리를 고르게끔 유인하셔야 해요
You'll guide her toward the
canary using a simulated trigger.
우리 보석들을 설명했을 때
When I was describing our gems,
로얄블루를 어떻게 가리켰는지
기억나세요?
did you notice how I pointed
out the royal blue?
엄지손가락을 펼쳐서 가리켰지
You gave it a thumbs up.
맞아요, 이 보석이 정말
좋은 물건이란 것을 은근히 가리킨거죠
Right, I was indicating
that this is a good item --
something you want.
고르게 하고픈 녀석을 말이죠
만족하세요?
Satisfied?
이건 꽤 좋네요
With this one.
5캐럿이나 6캐럿 정도는
남는 장사일거예요
That leaves you with a
five- or six-carat clear,
카나리색 아니면 분홍색 해보세요
the canary, or the pink.
세 번째 다이아몬드를
고르게 하는거야 말로
Now, getting her to
choose the third diamond
최고로 교묘한 단계에요
will be the trickiest.
그녀가 카나리를 감정하고 있는 동안에
While she's appraising the canary,
요원님은 못 알아 챌만큼 말장난을
하시기 시작하면 돼요
you'll start using muted word-play.
우리가 얘기하고 있었을 때
When you and I were talking,
전 블루랑 운이 맞는 단어들을
많이 말했었어요
I said a lot of words that rhyme with blue.
원 포인트 투, 블루, 트루
1.2.
Blue. True.
마지막 진짜 다이아몬드를
고르게 하시려면
So, while you're steering her
toward the last real diamond,
그 다이아몬드랑 운이 맞는
단어들을 말씀하셔야 해요
you'll start saying anything
that rhymes with...
핑크
Pink.
어떻게 생각하세요?
What do you think?
지금까진 훌륭해요
So far, so good.
같은 생각을 한다니 좋군요
Glad we're in sync.
이 거래가 끝날때...
When this deal's done...
나가서 축하라도 해야겠죠
...we should go out, celebrate...
한잔 해요
get a drink.
앞으로 바쁠 것 같아요
I have a busy day ahead.
다음에 해요
Next time.
이쯤되면 쿡이 드디어 등장할 만한
시간은 충분히 벌었을 거예요
At this point, enough time has passed
for Cook to make his grand entrance.
망할, 자네 대체 뭐하고 있는거야!
What the hell do you think you're doing?!
우리 게임을 끝내고 있지
Finishing our game.
내가 하던 일을 어떻게 알아냈는지
나는 잘 모르겠지만
I don't know how you did it --
how you found out what I was up to,
네 녀석을 부셔버릴거야, 모리스
but I'm gonna burn you for it, Morris.
좀 늦은 것 같은데
Oh, seems a little late now.
모든 선수들이 링 위에 올라서면
All the players are accounted for,
비로소 파트 3에 들어가는거예요
which brings us to phase three...
- 체포
The arrest.
쿡이 상점으로 들어갔어요
Cook's inside the store.
들어가도 되겠어요?
All right, can we move in?
다이아몬드를 가지고 왔는지
확인만 하면요
Once we have a visual on the diamonds.
금융회사 차렸다는 일이
얼토당토 않는다는 건 알고있었지
I knew that financial-firm
crap was a fairy tale.
그럴지도, 하지만 내가 말했듯이
한번 시작하면 끝을 보는 성격이야
Maybe so, but like I said,
once I start something,
I like to see it through.
이제 막판에 접어들었다고
This is the endgame.
녀석이 얼마를 제안하던가?
How much is he offering?
보아하니 28캐럿이니, 4백만달러요
Looks to be about 28 karats for $4 million.
내가 제안을 다시 하지
I'll counter-offer.
31 캐럿을 주고
I'll give you 31 karats...
380만 달러를 받겠어
But for $3.8 million.
- 다이아몬드 확인했어요!
- 출발 신호네요
I got eyes on the diamonds!
That's our go signal.
화이트칼라 수사국에 돌아오신 걸
환영합니다, 버크 요원
Welcome back to White Collar, agent Burke.
이봐, 이제 그만 가줬으면 하는데?
Hey, don't you have someplace else to be?
그거알아?
You know what?
이번 승리는 결국에는
내 것이 되지 않을 거야
This victory doesn't
belong to me after all.
- 내가 말했지 진짜 승부는...
- FBI다!
I told you those were the real deal.
FBI!
움직이지마!
Don't move!
데이비드 쿡, 너를 장물 소지죄로 체포한다
David Cook, you're under arrest
for the possession of stolen property.
고마워, 증거품으로 보관해줘요
Thank you. Secure the evidence.
요원님은 어디가셨죠?
Where's Peter?
내가 묻고 싶네요
Good question.
2분 늦었어
You're two minutes late.
신경쓸 일이 좀 있었거든요
I had to take care of something.
내 전화기 들을 신경쓰고 있어야
한다고 하지 않았나
You were supposed to be
taking care of my cellphones.
알고있죠
I know.
마감기한을 오늘 아침까지 주셨죠
You gave me a deadline for this morning.
그랬는데 자네가 그 작업을 어젯 밤에
다 끝내놔서 놀랐다네
That's why I'm impressed that
you finished them last night.
훌륭해
It's good work.
감사합니다
Thanks.
위원회에 올릴 자네 보고서에
지각은 쓰지 않아도 될 것 같군
So maybe I don't have to
mention you being late
in my report to your review board.
This time.
이번 만큼은
그것 참 잘됐네
Oh, that's good. Mmm.
우리가 침투하기 바로 전에
빠져나가셨다고 쿡이 말해주던 걸요
So, Cook told me you slipped
out just before we arrived.
응
Yeah.
왜 그곳에 계속 계시지 않으셨어요?
You want to tell me why
you didn't stick around?
I had a job to do.
해야할 일이 있었거든
This was your win, Peter.
이건 요원님 공이라고요, 피터
그래, 이 사건은 10년동안
나를 괴롭히던 녀석이었지
Yeah, this case has been
nagging at me for 10 years.
I got something better than a win.
승리보다 더 좋은 게 있더라고
What's that?
Closure.
그게 뭐죠?
사건종결
원래의 직위도 돌려받으셨어야죠
Well, you should have
gotten your job back, too.
두 마리 토끼를 잡을 순 없어
Can't have it both ways.
적어도 교도소 마당은
가지고 계시네요
Yeah, at least you still
got your yard for now.
우린 피크닉 에어리어로 부르거든
Yeah, we call it a picnic area.
My mistake.
제가 실수했네요
You know, you never did finish that story.
너 아직 그 얘기 다 안한거 알아?
무슨 얘기요?
What story?
네 아버지와 엘렌에 대해서 말야
The one about your dad, about Ellen.
Who was she to you?
그녀는 너에게 어떤 존재였어?
아버지가 떠나시고 나선
어머니는 바로 떠나셨어요
When my dad went away,
my mom just checked out.
주위에는 계신 것 같았는데
찾아 오시진 않으셨죠
I mean, she was around
but she wasn't...around.
그래서 엘렌이모가 절 돌봐주셨어요
So, Ellen looked after me.
그 분이 증인보호대상에 있으셨을텐데
어떻게 널 돌봐주신...
Well, how could she look after
you if she was in Witn--
너도 증인보호프로그램 속에서 자랐구나
You grew up in Witness Protection.
경찰관들이 저희를 데려간게 3살 때죠
I was 3 when the marshals took us away.
What did your dad do?
아버지는 대체 뭘 하신거야?
본인이 살인자라고 인정하셨어요
He admitted that he was a murderer.
그 분이 누구를...
Do you know who he --
No. No one ever told me.
몰라요, 아무도 말해주지 않았어요
어디로 갔었어?
Where'd you go?
세인트 루이스로 데려가더라고요
The marshals took us to St. Louis.
어머니와 엘렌, 그리고 저
It was my mom and Ellen and I,
and they changed my name to Danny Brooks.
제 이름을 대니 브룩스로 바꿔주더군요
어머니는 아버지께서 영웅이셨댔어요
My mom told me my dad died a hero.
잘 알지도 못하면서 그 분을
존경하면서 자라왔던 거죠
I grew up envying this man
that I never even knew.
I wanted to follow in his footsteps.
아버지의 뒤를 잇고 싶었죠
실제로 어느 정도는 그랬던 것 같아요
In a way, I guess I did.
No, you didn't. You're not a killer.
아냐, 그렇지 않아
넌 살인자가 아니잖아
No. No, but I'm a criminal.
아니죠, 하지만 범죄자가 됐죠
When I was 18, Ellen told me the truth.
18살 때, 이모님이 진실을 들려주셨죠
제 본명이 닐 이라고도요
She told me my real name was Neal.
Your mother's maiden name was Caffrey.
어머님 결혼 전 성함이 카프리였고
아버지의 이름을 갖고 싶지 않았죠
Well, I couldn't take his name.
제가 진실을 알고나서 부터는요
Not after I knew.
So that's when Neal Caffrey was born.
닐 카프리가 탄생했던 순간이군
After she told me everything, I
ran and I never looked back.
진실을 다 듣고 나서 도망치곤
다시 돌아오지 않았었죠
하지만 이젠, 알고 싶어요
그 분이 어떤 분이셨는지
But now I want to know. I
want to know who he was.
알고싶어요...
I want to know...
정말 그러셨던 건지 알고 싶어요
I want to know if he did it.
그 분이 여기 계시니까
Well, Ellen's here now.
여쭤봐
Go find out.
닐, 내가 이 얘기를 해준다면
Neal, if I tell you this,
솔직히 나로서는 닫아두는 게
최선이라고 생각했던 문을 여는거야
it may open doors
that I honestly believe
are best kept closed.
아버지를 체포하셨었잖아요
무슨일이 있었던 거예요?
You arrested him. What happened?
동료 경찰관에게서 전화를 받은
어떤 밤이었단다
One night I got a call
from a fellow officer.
그 남자가 말하길 제임스가
비밀리에 만나자고 했다더구나
He said James had asked for
an "off the books" meeting.
- 내게 지원을 요청한거야
- 그리고요?
He wanted backup.
Then what?
내가 그곳에 도착했을 땐
그 남자는 죽어있었어
By the time I got there,
the officer was dead.
네 아버지의 지문이 묻은
총을 발견했었지
We found a gun with his prints on it.
경찰을 죽이셨던 거예요?
He killed a cop?
- 자긴 무죄라고 하더구나
- 믿어주셨어요?
He said he was innocent.
Did you believe him?
제임스를 가리켰던 증거가 많았어
James was many things,
하지만 그 사람이 넘지 않을
선이 있다고 생각했던 나는
but I thought there were
lines he wouldn't cross.
조사를 하게 됐고
엄청난 무언가를 발견해 냈지
I investigated.
I was onto something big.
그런데 그가 자백하고 만거야
But then he confessed.
그 분이 죽이셨을까요?
Did he do it?
오래된 일이란다
It was a long time ago.
엘렌, 그 분이 어떤 사람인지
알고 싶어요
Ellen, I need to understand who he was.
아버지라면 넘지 않을 선이란게
있었다고 말씀하셨잖아요
You said there were lines my
father would never cross,
but he did.
하지만 하신거죠
I need to know who I am.
내가 어떤 사람인지 알고 싶어요
한글수정: sweetmin
해설/피드백:khbs22.tistory.com